A Guide to the Papers of Dr. Forrest P. White 1952-1963
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Papers of Dr. Forrest P. White 1952-1963
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
MG 5
Two Hollinger Documents Cases
Dr. Forrest P. White
Administrative Information
Access
Open to researchers without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Dr. Forrest P. White April 1976
Biographical/Historical Information
Dr. Forrest P. White was born in Norfolk in 1920. He graduated from Randolph-Macon College and the Medical College of Virginia. He served his internship in the United States Navy (1945-1946) and then served in the Medical Corps of the United States Naval Reserve (1946-1947). He served his residency at the Medical College of Virginia Hospitals from 1948 to 1950 and became a practicing pediatrician in Norfolk, Virginia. Dr. White was active in local politics in Norfolk and played a central role in the formation and running of the Norfolk Committee for Public Schools, an organization which opposed the closing of that city's public schools during the desegregation crisis of the late 1950's and early 1960's. He died on March 26, 1995 at his home in Norfolk.
Scope and Content Information
The bulk of the material concerns the desegregation of Norfolk, Virginia's public schools. There is some material on the Gray Commission Report (1955-1956), much more on the Norfolk Committee for Public Schools, an organization in which Dr. White was active from 1958 to 1963. The latter material includes correspondence, publicity releases, financial records, and newspaper clippings. There are small amounts of material on the 1952 Byrd-Miller Democratic Senatorial primary and on the 1961 Citizens for Democratic Government campaign in Norfolk's Democratic primary.
Contents List
- Series I: General
  - Virginia Politics: Democratic Senatorial Contest; General Election 1952 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 1)
  - School Desegregation: Gray Commission Report; Miscellaneous Material 1955-1956 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 2)
  - School Desegregation: Gray Commission Report, Newspaper Clippings 1955-1956 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II: Norfolk Committtee for Public Schools
  - General Correspondence 1958-1962 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Official Communications 1958-1963 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Financial Records: Correspondence re. Finances 1958-1963 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Financial Records: Invoices; Miscellaneous Bills; Bank Account Records 1958-1960 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Financial Records: People Contacted for Contributions; Records re. Contributions 1958-1960 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Checks, Deposit Slips undated (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Membership Cards undated (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Essays re. Massive Resistance in Norfolk and Prince Edward County, Virginia undated (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Organizing to Save Public Schools" - Virginia Committee for Public Schools undated (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Material 1958-1961 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Perrow Report to Governor of Virginia 1959 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Involvement in Barfield, Shepheard Races for City Council 1960 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings Pre-1958 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings re. School Crisis 1958 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings re. School Crisis 1958 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings re. Massive Resistance and Norfolk School Closings 1958 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings re. School Crisis 1959 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Misc. Newspaper Clipings re. School Crisis 1959 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings re. Norfolk Schools Reopened undated (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings re. Massive Resistance, Norfolk School Closings, Gov. J. Lindsay Almond 1958-1964 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Letters to the Editor re. Norfolk School Closings 1958-1959 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Letters to the Editor, Statements 1958-1959 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Paid Advertisements 1958-1959 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Virginia Committee for Public Schools: Official Communications 1959-1960 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Citizens for Democratic Government (Norfolk): Miscellaneous Material 1961 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Look, "The South vs. The Supreme Court" 3 April 1956 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Mrs. Edith White - Correspondence - Governor Thomas B. Stanley Nov. 1956 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 15)